AKSHAY G

Front-End Developer | JavaScript | React JS | Html | Css

+91 8754070533

mailto.akshay.dev@gmail.com

Gummidipoondi, Chennai

SUMMARY

Persevering learner and diligent team player with 2 years of experience specializing in UI development using the React library. Skilled software engineer with expertise in AI-powered recruiting applications, HRMS, ticket management, educational timeline systems, and ERP applications. You can view my *portfolio* here.

SKILLS

Javascript, Typescript, HTML, CSS, React.Js, Bootstrap, Redux, Redux Saga, React Router,

Git, GitHub, Bit bucket, Rest, Axios, Fetch, Scss, Firebase, i18n-js, Jitsi, validate.js,

React-player, React-photo-view, React-DND, React-Select

EXPERIENCE

React JS Developer - 06/2022 - Present

Leora Infotech Private Limited - Gummidipoondi, Chennai.

- Responsible for frontend design and development
- Proficient in developing UI for web applications primarily on React JS
- Skilled in developing modular components to ensure scalability and maintainability
- Collaborate effectively with UI/UX designers to implement designs that enhance user experience
- Proactively troubleshoot and debug issues to ensure smooth functioning of applications
- Stay updated with the latest technologies through continuous research and self-learning
- Oversee testing protocols to maintain the quality and reliability of applications

Payment Assistance - 30/09/2021 - 14/03/2022

MATRIMONY.COM LIMITED - Guindy, Chennai.

• Utilizing chat and system calls, I addressed user concerns, convinced them of

package benefits, and ensured a smooth transaction experience.

Data Provisioning Executive - 01/2019 - 11/2019

Tenth Planet Technologies - Mount Road, Chennai.

• Provide customized enterprise IT solutions, centered around open source software, troubleshoot issues, and ensure compliance.

Process Associate - 04/2017 - 11/2017

String Information Services - Saidapet, Chennai.

• Mortgage Process Outsourcing (MPO) - tailored solutions, optimize and streamline mortgage processes, enhance efficiency, reduce costs.

PROJECTS

INTRVU SPACE — Hiring Application (AI) | Link

• intrvu SPACE helps you conduct automated Interviews, Generate Reports, and Approve Candidates end to end with zero manual effort.

Contribution: Landing page, Login, OTP, Corporate flow, CRUD candidate flow, Settings, Job seeker flow, Report

Tech Stack: React, Redux, Redux Saga, React Router, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, Validate.js

Zeny Q — HRMS | Link

 Employee management application with features like attendance and payroll management.

Contribution: Api integration and data normalization, Salary slip.

Tech Stack: React, Redux, Redux Saga, React Router, Bootstrap, push notification.

Quanta TMS — Ticket Management Solution | Link

• Enhances task and ticket management for improved collaboration.

Contribution: Login, OTP, Individual & Group chats, Task, Ticket, Association, Feeds, Event

Tech Stack: React, Redux, Redux Saga, React Router, Bootstrap, Validate.js, push notification.

Quanta EDAT — EduTech Application | Link

• Offers comprehensive programming courses with practical tasks and mock interviews.

Contribution: Course CRUD, Tasks, Topics, Schedule Interview, Online Sessions
Tech Stack: React, Redux, Redux Saga, React Router, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Validate.js.

NS Instruments - FG — Finished Goods Management

• Optimises inventory control with streamlined stock and product management.

Contribution: Login, OTP, Dispatch request, Stock request and Paginated Listing Tech Stack: React, Redux, Redux Saga, React Router, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Validate.js, push notification.

EDUCATION

Bsc Computer Science - 2013 - 2016 Shree Chandraprabhu Jain College Minjur, Chennai.

XII (HSS) - 2011 -2013

St.Marys Matric Hr Sec Chinthala Kuppam, Gummidipoondi.

X (SSLC) - 2010 - 2011

Shanthiniketan Matric Hr Sec New Gummidipoondi.

LANGUAGES

Tamil: Mother Tongue English: Professional (Conversationally fluent)

Malayalam: Conversationally fluent Hindi: Writing and Reading